Vibhushit Sharma 🔘 Featured

B.Tech. (C.S.E), having 10 years of experience in java: Spring Boot, Microservices, Spring, Hibernate in HCL Technologies.



Current Designation: Lead Engineer Total Experience: 10 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: HCL Infosystems Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [C.S.E.]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Key Skills: Software Development, Core JAVA (J2SE5) and J2EE., Microservices, Spring Boot, Hibernate, Oracle

Verified: Email - id

Last Active: 24-Dec-20 Last Modified: 24-Dec-20

Summary

Overall 10 Yrs of experience.

core java 1.8, struts1.2, JDBC, spring2.0, hibernate3.0, JNDI, microservices, spring boot, oracle.

Ability to grasp new technology and tools quickly.

Worked on various projects using Java (J2SE5)/J2EE1.5, JDBC, JSP, Servlet, Java Beans, XML and JNDI, spring, hibernate with Oracle9i and MySQL1.5, Apache poi3.7, Sshxcute1.0.

Proficiency to MVC-2 Architecture

Used tomoat 6.0 for web server and JBoss6 for application server and Oracle as the Backend Database on a window Operating System.

Worked on IDE such as Myeclipse6.0, Eclipse3.3.2.

Applications consisted of a JSP Web Interface using the Model View Controller pattern.

Primarily worked on all areas of development, including building the Middle and Backend Components using Data Access Objects, Pojo classes managed with Spring Container with Hibernate as an ORM tool.

Extensive background in designing persistence layer of application which includes creating Entities, mapping Files in Hibernate

Work Experience

HCL Infosystems as Lead Engineer

Nov 2014 to Till Date

Worked in creating Spring Boot Microservices, Spring, Hibernate, Rest Based services

Eka Software Services as Software Developer

Jul 2013 to Jul 2014

Projects

Patch Management Tool Aug 2013- Sept 2013

Team Size:2

Organization: Eka Software Solution Pvt. Ltd.

Location: Bangalore

Technologies: Core Java, J2EE, Hibernate, Dozer API, Spring, Struts 2.0, Jsp, Servlets

, Junit , Maven , PL/SQL , Javascript ,Html, Ajax

Description: Patch Tool is used by config team to apply code patches to appropriate environment

based on reading a patch file in patch folder .

Responsibilities:

- . Worked in designing persistence layer of application including mapping files, configuration files
- . Worked in Presentation layer creating JSP pages, JavaScript functions involved. Junit Testing of service and DAO components involved.

CTRM (Commodity Trading and Risk Management) Oct 2013- till Date

Team Size: 7

Organization: Eka Software Solution Pvt. Ltd.

Location: Bangalore

Technologies: Core Java, J2EE, Hibernate, Sql, Spring, Struts, Jsp, Servlets, Junit, Maven, PL/SQL, Javascript

,Html

Description: CTRM is an end-to-end commodity management platform covering trading and position management, physical supply chain, enterprise risk management and compliance and analytics. CTRM works across the agriculture, energy and metals and mining sectors with customers that include many large commodity marketers, traders, miners and manufacturers.

Responsibilities:

- * Worked on the Risk Component which aims to define, measure and control organization wide risk
- * Involved in the analysis and study of the requirement specifications, development, coding and Junit testing.
- * Involved in enhancements and fixing bugs.

Achievements:

Received appreciations from on shore team on the completion of enhancements single handedly.

CenturyLink India Software Services as Software Developer

Jun 2010 to Jun 2013

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (C.S.E.) from Punjab Technical University (PTU) in 2003

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

SCJP 1.5 (Sun Certified Java Programmer)

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Win9X/NT/ XP/2003, Window Vista	
Junit , Maven	
Tomcat6.0	
C++, Core JAVA, J2EE, UML, XML	
JDBC, Servlet, JSP, struts1.2, spring2.0	
Apache POI 3.7, Sshxcute1.0	
НТТР	
UML	

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time